<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abhinav&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Abhinav&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 16:16:24 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/hugo-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hugo-gallery/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll add in my keybase.io profile here soon, but you can email me @ sabhinav at bu dot edu. I live stream my consiousness on this awesome website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encrypting a partition and exporting it as rootfs</title>
      <link>/blog/encrypt-rootfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/encrypt-rootfs/</guid>
      <description>Step 1: Creating a Virtual Disk To begin, we&amp;rsquo;ll create a virtual disk image that will act as our encrypted partition. We can use the dd command to create a file of a specified size filled with zeros:
dd if=/dev/zero of=virtual_disk.img bs=1M count=1024  This command creates a file named &amp;ldquo;virtual_disk.img&amp;rdquo; with a size of 1024 megabytes (1 GB).
Step 2: Associating the Virtual Disk with a Loop Device Next, we need to make the virtual disk image accessible as a block device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does an Ethereum Transaction work?</title>
      <link>/blog/tx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/tx/</guid>
      <description>A Blockchain is essentially a public database in which the data is shared and synchronized across multiple nodes connected in a network. A Blockchain is built up of Block Data structures arranged in a Chain like cryptographic sequence.
Ethereum is no different, when you commit any transaction on the chain, the data must be added to the network for it to be successful. The verification process is similar to Bitcoin, which uses Proof of Work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build and Boot a Custom Linux Kernel Using QEMU Without Risking Your System</title>
      <link>/blog/linux-kernel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/linux-kernel/</guid>
      <description>READ BEFORE COPY PASTING COMMANDS!
 QEMU is a powerful open-source machine emulator and virtualizer. We don&amp;rsquo;t wan to play around too much on our system, so best to use QEMU. Before starting, ensure QEMU is installed on your system. Installation commands vary by distribution:
 Debian/Ubuntu: sudo apt-get install qemu  Obtain the latest Linux kernel source from kernel.org. Extract the archive and prepare for compilation:
git clone https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India shouldn&#39;t fight the AI war</title>
      <link>/blog/india-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/india-ai/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical spirits and spiritual machines</title>
      <link>/blog/spiritual-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/spiritual-machines/</guid>
      <description>[under construction]
Notes:
 A note about Doom Guy, the book A history of BeOS About Haiku A few anecdotes of older engineers Comparing modern SDEs to Civil Engineers Bloat in software AI, Crypto, etc. Books: In the beginning was the command line.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Education   ** University of Colorado Boulder** (part time)
 Boulder, CO Aug 2024–May 2026 MS in Electrical Engineering, focus on FPGA, Embedded Engineering, Semiconductors    Boston University
 Boston, MA Sep 2022–Jan 2024 MS in Computer Science, spl. CyberSecurity    Vellore Institute of Technology
 Vellore, India May 2021 BS in Computer Science &amp;amp; Engineering    Work Experience   Mentee @ RISC-V, Remote (Mar 2024 - May 2024)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure Multi-Party Computation for predicting healthcare costs</title>
      <link>/research/smpc_healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/smpc_healthcare/</guid>
      <description>\documentclass{article} % Language setting % Replace `english&#39; with e.g. `spanish&#39; to change the document language \usepackage[english]{babel} % Set page size and margins % Replace `letterpaper&#39; with `a4paper&#39; for UK/EU standard size \usepackage[letterpaper,top=2cm,bottom=2cm,left=3cm,right=3cm,marginparwidth=1.75cm]{geometry} % Useful packages \usepackage{amsmath} \usepackage{graphicx} \usepackage[colorlinks=true, allcolors=blue]{hyperref} \title{Using Secure Multiparty Computing to predict cost of healthcare clinic visits} \author{Abhinav Srivastava} \begin{document} \maketitle \begin{abstract} Secure Multiparty Computing (SMC) offers a privacy-preserving method for predicting healthcare clinic visit costs. Utilizing SMC, sensitive patient data is processed across multiple parties without revealing individual inputs, ensuring confidentiality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The weird people of social media</title>
      <link>/blog/antisocialmedia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/antisocialmedia/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Torment Nexus - or why we don&#39;t take advice from writers</title>
      <link>/blog/torment-nexus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/torment-nexus/</guid>
      <description>While the title may seem disrespectful, I want to clarify that I respect writers. Chekov, King, Liu, Stephenson, Gaiman, Herbert, Crichton, Guin, have all written books that have personally influenced me deeply. I love their work, and I respect their craft. But I don&amp;rsquo;t take advice from them, because they&amp;rsquo;re not engineers who are currently building the present.
Charlie Stoss wrote the blog titled &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re sorry we created the Torment Nexus&amp;rdquo;, in which he writes &amp;ldquo;I—and other SF authors—are terrible guides to the future&amp;rdquo; - and I agree, but not in the way Stoss presents it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a lexer for C in Ocaml</title>
      <link>/blog/lexer-ocaml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/lexer-ocaml/</guid>
      <description>ref. Nora Sandler&amp;rsquo;s, Writing a C Compiler, Part 1
This is my first time using Ocaml, and Dune. If this is the case with you, if you want a primer, you can read the official docs, and then do 99 Problems and get back here, although 3 problems in, I said &amp;ldquo;Bah! I got this&amp;rdquo; and infact, I didn&amp;rsquo;t. You can read this bit, and implement parsers in the next one on your own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero Knowledge proofs on Y-STR Data for forensic DNA analysis</title>
      <link>/research/zk-dna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/zk-dna/</guid>
      <description>WIP - DM if you&amp;rsquo;d want to collaborate on this.
\documentclass{article} \usepackage{lipsum} % For generating dummy text \usepackage{amsmath,amssymb} \usepackage{tikz} \usetikzlibrary{arrows,shapes.geometric,positioning} % Set up for two-column layout \begin{document} \title{Using interactive zero-knowledge proofs for negative STR DNA match proof} \author{\IEEEauthorblockN{Abhinav S.}\\ \IEEEauthorblockA{Boston University\\ Email: sabhinav@bu.edu} } \maketitle \begin{abstract} This paper explores the application of zero-knowledge proofs in genetic authentication, specifically in forensic settings. In environments where a trusted central authority is assumed to have the individuals&#39; best privacy-oriented interests at heart, zero-knowledge proofs offer a compelling method for secure identity verification.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
